<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on California Dreaming</title>
    <link>https://binnz.github.io/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on California Dreaming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://binnz.github.io/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Practice in R: Analysis on all individuals diagnosed with Type I diabetes</title>
      <link>https://binnz.github.io/post/2018-09-10-r3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binnz.github.io/post/2018-09-10-r3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Diabetes Registry Study targeted all individuals $&amp;lt;30$ years of age diagnosed with Type I diabetes in southern Wisconsin, USA. Participants were requested to submit blood samples and were sent a questionnaire inquiring about hospitalizations and other events. The blood samples were used to determine glycosylated hemoglobin (GHb), and important indicator of glycemic control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data set &lt;code&gt;diabetes.txt&lt;/code&gt;, which can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ghuang.stat.nctu.edu.tw/course/datasci17/files/data/diabetes.txt&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, contains the data from the Wisconsin Diabetes Registry Study. The data items are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Variable name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;an unique identification number&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HEALTH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;self-reported health status: 1=excellent, 2=good, 3=fair, 4=poor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;dichotomized health status: 1=excellent health, 0=worse than excellent health&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GENDER&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;sex code: 1=female, 0=male&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GHb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;overal mean glycosylated hemoglobin value in study&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AGE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;age at diagnosis (years)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the section &amp;ldquo;Relationship of GHb with age&amp;rdquo;, we are interested in the relationship of GHb with age at diagnosis and/or self-reported health status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the section &amp;ldquo;Modeling of dichotomized health status&amp;rdquo;, we use BH as the dependent variable (response variable) and use models such as logistic regression to show the explanationary power of other independent variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice in R: Insights on Poverty</title>
      <link>https://binnz.github.io/post/2018-09-10-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binnz.github.io/post/2018-09-10-poverty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This practice is based on Hans Rosling talks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/hans_rosling_reveals_new_insights_on_poverty?language=en&#34;&gt;New Insights on Poverty&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/hans_rosling_shows_the_best_stats_you_ve_ever_seen&#34;&gt;The Best Stats You&amp;rsquo;ve Ever Seen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assignment uses data to answer specific question about global health and economics. The data contradicts commonly held preconceived notions. For example, Hans Rosling starts his talk by asking: &amp;ldquo;for each of the six pairs of countries below, which country do you think had the highest child mortality in 2015?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sri Lanka or Turkey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poland or South Korea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Malaysia or Russia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pakistan or Vietnam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thailand or South Africa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people get them wrong. Why is this? In part it is due to our preconceived notion that the world is divided into two groups: the
&lt;em&gt;Western world&lt;/em&gt; versus the &lt;em&gt;third world&lt;/em&gt;, characterized by &amp;ldquo;long life,small family&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;short life, large family&amp;rdquo; respectively. In this homework we will use data visualization to gain insights on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice in R: Monte Carlo Simulation &amp; Central Limit Theorem (CLT)</title>
      <link>https://binnz.github.io/post/2018-09-10-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binnz.github.io/post/2018-09-10-r2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a practice in R for realization of Monte Carlo Simulation, Central Limit Theorem (CLT), normal approximation, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining - Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://binnz.github.io/post/2017-11-07-anomaly-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binnz.github.io/post/2017-11-07-anomaly-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anomalies, or say outliers, are the set of data points that are considerably different than the remainder of the data.   Common applications of anomaly detection are credit card fraud detection, telecommunication fraud detection, network intrusion detection, fault detection, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The working assumption of anomaly detection is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are considerably more “normal” observations than “abnormal” observations (outliers/anomalies) in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Time Series Analysis and Models</title>
      <link>https://binnz.github.io/post/2017-03-20-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binnz.github.io/post/2017-03-20-time-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series&lt;/strong&gt;: A time series is a series of data points indexed (or listed or graphed) in time order.   A sequence taken at successive equally spaced points in time (A sequence of discrete-time data).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: Methods for analyzing time series data in order to extract meaningful statistics and other characteristics of the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series forecasting&lt;/strong&gt;: The use of a model to predict future values based on previously observed values.   While regression analysis is often employed in such a way as to test theories that the current values of one or more independent time series affect the current value of another time series, Time series forecasting focuses on comparing values of a single time series or multiple dependent time series at different points in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series modeling&lt;/strong&gt;: It involves working on time (years, days, hours, minutes) based data, to derive hidden insights to make informed decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
